98% of professionals want remote work at
least once in their careers because
remote work has no commute, flexible
hours, and total freedom. But are they
ready for it? With great flexibility
comes the challenges of
miscommunication, workflow confusion,
and even difficulty in performance
tracking. Despite all these challenges,
the right collaboration tips can keep
your team productive, connected, and on
track. Let's dive into the best ways to
manage remote teamwork smoothly and
stress-free. To collaborate better with
your team, the first thing you need to
do is manage things smartly. Setting
goals that are specific, measurable,
attainable, relevant, and time bound
smart is the key to successful remote
team collaboration. Once you know what
to achieve and how much time you have to
do that, you can step into another great
team collaboration technique,
communication. Working remotely means
your designer might be in New York or
maybe your developer in China and your
marketer in London. Different time
zones, different work styles, and
different mindset. That's a recipe for
miscommunication. So, how do we fix it?
Simple. Use a centralized project
management tool. First of all, it makes
onboarding team members effortless
despite being from different regions of
the globe. With easy onboarding, you can
manage their rules and limit their
access to your project board so that
they can see only what they are supposed
to see. If your project management tool
lets you secure back-end operations and
manage everything from the front end
like Fluent Boards, it's definitely a
big plus. Once you have your goals set
and team members on boarded, you can
focus on dividing your project work into
multiple stages like planning, ongoing,
done, and also achievable tasks. Then
you can easily assign the right person
to get it done with a clear deadline and
priority. So no more guesswork. To guide
them even better, you can write a
description to complete the task
perfectly and attach necessary
documentation or files that can assist
them in finishing it effortlessly.
Besides, to speed up the task
completion, you can even set an
estimated time and let the assenee log a
time so that you can know how much time
he is spending on the task. In case
you're worried about tracking the
performance of your remote worker, a
tool like Fluent Boards can be a
lifesaver for you. There are some other
perks of having a project management
tool. If any task takes longer than the
expected time, you can divide the task
into subtasks to get it done
effortlessly. To resolve any issue
instantly, you can get realtime updates
from your team members easily. In case
you need to repeat any task regularly,
you can convert it into a recurring task
easily. Once any task is completed,
easily move it to another stage in just
a snap. While a tool can boost your team
collaboration by many a mile, you need a
good project manager or team lead to
manage them and get your projects done
in time. A successful remote
collaboration stays on the top with
someone who values all the unique
perspectives and ideas coming to the
table. If you have a great team, the
right person to lead, and a tool like
Fluent Boards to make collaboration
easier, managing a remote team becomes a
lot easier. So, stop letting remote work
slow you down. Take control, streamline
your workflow, and bring your team
together effortlessly with Fluent
Boards. Install it now.
[Music]